Guide to the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Subject Files and Photographs, 1888-2004
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Subject Files and Photographs, 1888-2004
- Series XIII. Graphics and Audiovisual Material
  - American Veterinary Medical Association (AVMA) Convention, Indianapolis, Indiana; 6 rows; women in 2nd row with large hats., September 26-31, 1912 (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - External Parasites Infesting the Dog (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Two sketches of the architecture of the Veterinary School (Mapcase-folder 2)
  - Large hand drawn illustration of an internal organ (Mapcase-folder 2)
  - Large Image of T. Smith (1859-1934) (Mapcase-folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Films, some of college scenes, some of faculty research, some unidentified (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Films, some of college scenes, some of faculty research, some unidentified (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Films, some of college scenes, some of faculty research, some unidentified (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Films, some of college scenes, some of faculty research, some unidentified (Box 15)
  - Several film reels, including the ones put into the cornerstone of the new Veterinary College, and other assorted film rolls, 1953-1958, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Film reels on Gains Dog Research Center,Rabies, and assorted other film reels, 1952-1958 (Box 11)
  - Studies of Feline Respiratory Viruses in Tissue Culture Systems (Box 14)
    Photographs
  - Film reels on faculty and "71 Valiant Years", 1934-1935, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Film reel of Faculty, 1932; F-1617 (Box 37)
  - Caricatures made for Honor Day Banquet by Vincent Paciello, 1940 (Box 16)
  - Animal Table Decorations for Honor Day Banquet by Rebecca Gifford, 1940 (Box 17)
  - Historical Post Cards (Box 21)
- Series XIV. Miscellaneous
  - Honor Code (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Logo, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Medical College (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Polo (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Veterinary Education (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Veterinary Education-"Suggestive Comments on Veterinary Education..." by Alumni, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Veterinary Profession (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Veterinary Reserve Corps and ROTC (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Tuberculin Record Book, 1922-1928 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Record of sales of TB tests made by the College
  - Visitors-Guest Books, 1951-1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Visitors-Guest books, 1960-1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Women in the College (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Proclamations and Legislative Resolutions, 1980, 1982, 1994, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Governor's Citations, 1982, 1994, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Visitors - Guestbooks, 1967-1989 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Visitors - Guestbook, 1957-1978 (Box 19)
  - News Clippings, 1896, 1904, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - News Clippings - oversized, 1902 (Box 9)
  - News Clippings, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - News Clippings, 1940-1943 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - News Clippings, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - News Clippings, 1946-1949, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - News Clippings, 1950-1959 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - News Clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - News Clippings, 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - News Clippings, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - News Clippings, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - News Clippings, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - News Clippings, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - News Clippings - oversized, 1970s and 1980s (Box 9)
  - News Clippings, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - News Clippings, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - News Clippings, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Visitors-Guest Book, 1957-1978 (Box 19)
  - Unidentified handwritten abstracts, ca. 1890s (Box 22)
  - College Centennial Calendar, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 37)
  - College Note Cards and Stationery with College Images, 1990s (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Dr. Joseph Dye's medals, 1929, 1952; MU-1540 (Box 37)
  - Dean William Hagen's paperweight, no date; MU-1543 (Box 37)
  - Cooper print plate, photo negative of faculty, no date; MU-1541 (Box 37)
  - Surgical Instruments made by Leach and Green of England and Scotland and presented to John P. Burke in 1961, no date; MU-1542 (Box 37)
  - Photographs and Slides
  - Avian, no dates (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Bovine, 1980s-1990s (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Dogs, 1980s-1990s (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Equine - some slides, 1980s-2003 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Exotic Wildlife, 1970s-2001 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Exotic Wildlife - slides, 1980s-2000 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Felines, 1970s-1990s (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Felines - slides, 1990s (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - General Microbiology, 1980s (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Horses - Slides, 1980s-2001 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Infectious Disease - slides, 1980s (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - Mice - slides, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - Objects - slides, 1990s (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - People - slides and CDs, 1990s-2004 (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - People - slides, 1980s-2004 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - People, 1980s-2001 (Box 34, Folder 36)
  - People and Pets - some slides, 1980s-1990s (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Radiology - some slides, 1990s-2000 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Research - some slides, 2000s (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Science Images - some slides, no dates (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Surgery - Slides, 1970s-2001 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Woodchucks, no dates (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Artwork in College, 1997-2001 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Bookmark, no date (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - "A Century of Bovine Medicine at Cornell" - Draft - Eileen Roberts, 2001 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Logo, no date (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Daniel Salmon Charcoal Etching - Conservation Information, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Timeline - History, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Signed photo of Helen Keller, thanking Dr. Trelford Miller for taking care of her two dogs, March 1, 1932 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous people and building exterior, H.K. Fuller (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Engraving of French veterinary painting by Seeldrayer, Undated (Box 46, Folder 63)
  - Postcard of Captain Corwin (Louis A Corwin DVM '19), 1919 (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Three baseball players on field in Stewart Park; Ithaca Falls and bridge in background, Undated (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Dr. Corwin at 2nd base, Undated (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Catcher and umpire at plate during Cornell-Columbia game, Undated (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Two on horses outside farriery building at Vet College, Undated (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Two rows of Cornell baseball players on freshman team, Undated (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Two rows of Cornell baseball players, Undated (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Numerous negatives of Cornell athletics, Undated (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - Ezra Cornell seating in fancy chair facing right, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: A01-01-0012
  - Ezra Cornell portrait facing left, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: A01-01-0002
  - Ezra Cornell portrait facing left, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: 800.C814
  - Andrew Dickson White portrait facing left, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: 800.W582
  - First Cornell faculty composite; Dr James Law upper left at 11 o'clock facing right, 1869 (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: A11-11-1868-9
  - Cornell University faculty; Dr James Law in front row far right, 1889 (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: A11-3-ph80
  - Sage College tennis court with 4 women students, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - Dr Edmund Day pointing to Cornell college enrollment poster at Gcc meeting in Olin Hall, 1948 (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - Rows of Cornell students in stands covered with mud, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: 37-9-ph29
  - Spring day showing students dancing in devil costumes in street, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: 37-7-ph111
  - AD White pushing shovel with LH Bailey standing in center breakding ground for agricultural buildings, 1905 (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: A01-02-003
  - Spring day with cars lined up outside Schoelkopf Cresent stadium, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: 37-7-ph94
  - Digging foundation for Roberts Hall agricultural buildings, summer 1905, 1905 (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - View of Ithaca and Cornell's Morrill Hall (left) Cascadilla Hall (right) on hill from Clinton Hotel tower, 1868, 1868 (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - Group photo of Cornell faculty in front of Barton Hall; Dr James Law in f ront row 4th fron left in light suit??, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - Engraving of Cornell campus showing surveyors on Arts Quad with Morrill Hall in foreground, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: N1538
  - Students playing in mud on athletic field, 1925 (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - Soldiers congregated on Arts Quad in front of Goldwin Smith Hall, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - Students in beanie hats in athletic stands, Undated (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: APC#6835
  - Faculty and administrative officers 1932, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - View looking north on Libe Slope with Sage Hall on right, 1875 (Box 46, Folder 65)
    Item number: APC#1579
  - Cornell faculty on steps in front of Bailey Hall; Dean William A Hagan in front row seated 3rd from left, 1949 (Box 46, Folder 65)
  - Cover of Cornell Veterinarian, vol. 1 no 1, June 1911, Undated (Box 46, Folder 66)
  - Book by James Law, Farmer's Veterinary Advisor, standing up with open pages, Undated (Box 46, Folder 66)
  - W.W. Armistead, Undated (Box 47, Folder 36)
    Item number: 600.A729
  - Floyd Cross, Undated (Box 47, Folder 36)
    Item number: 600.C951
  - John R. McCoy, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Brig. Gen. Wayne O. Kester, Undated (Box 47, Folder 36)
    Item number: 600.K42
  - Mrs. Daniel Paradee (Women's Auxiliary), Undated (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Roger P. Link AVMA president-elect, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Esther S. Bondareff with several unknown men under tent, Undated (Box 47, Folder 38)
    Item number: 051020-R5-16
  - Susan Long and other unidentified veterinary technician in Clinical Sciences Dept - Veterinary Medical Teaching Hospital, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 38)
    Item number: A30103-14-28A
  - Elizabeth Kraft, Undated (Box 47, Folder 38)
    Item number: 11358
  - Dr W Medway in labortory, Undated (Box 47, Folder 38)
    Item number: 11401
  - Mildred Zein, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 38)
    Item number: 11362
  - Eileen Wainwright, telephone operator in 1980s, Undated (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Man in hat seated on a heavy wagon harnessed to two dark horses [this could be the College's utility wagon used by the large animal surgery; driver is unidentified], Undated (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Roswell P. Flower (no signature), Undated (Box 47, Folder 37)
    Item number: 3-194-78
  - Roswell P. Flower with signature, Undated (Box 47, Folder 37)
    Item number: 36-197-93
  - Signature and inscription by Roswell P. Flower, Undated (Box 47, Folder 37)
    Item number: 6-197A-93
  - Portrait of Ilya Illyich (Elie) Metchnikoff (1845-1916, Russian zoologist and winner of 1908 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine, 1905 (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Portrait of __ Barnes, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Portrait of Leonard Pearson, professor at University of Pennsylvania School of Veterinary Medicine (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 240.361
  - Portrait of Dr. Bennet T. Simms, last chief of the US Bureau of Animal Industry, US Deptment of Agriculture, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.S592
  - Portrait of Dr. F.L. Hershenroeder, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1958 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.H571
  - Portrait of Jean Broadhurst, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 800.B863
  - Postcard with portrait of Robert Koch sent from Germany to Dean William A Hagan, 1932 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 800.K76
  - Portrait of Dr. Hadleigh Marsh of Helena, Montana, winner of the 12th International Veterinary Congress Prize, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.M365
  - Portrait of Dr. Duncan McEachran, Dean of Montreal Veterinary College, 1921 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.M141
  - Portrait of Dr Gerhard Forsall of Stockholm, Sweden (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.F732
  - Portrait of Sir Arnold Theiler, 1925 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.T376
  - Portrait of Professor W. Zwick, formerly of the Giessen veterinary college faculty in Germany, 1944 (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.Z98
  - Portrait of Lewellyn F. Barker, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 800.B255
  - Portrait of Professor E.H. Starling, a British physiologist, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Portrait of Alexander Liautard, a French veterinarian who practiced and taught veterinary medicine in New York City (signed), Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.L693
  - Portrait of Dr George H.Berns, veterinarian from New York City, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.B422
  - Portrait of Professor Dr. Wilhelm Ellenberger, a German anatomist, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Portrait of Sir Frederick Smith of the Royal Veterinary College, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Portrait of Dr. W. M. Bayliss, British zoologist and parasitologist, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Portrait of C. H. Case, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Portrait of Dr. Andrew Smith, founder of the Ontario Veterinary College, Undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
    Item number: 600.S642
  - Dr Fred D Maurer - 12th International Veterinary Congress, Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Eight color photos of veterinary students in extracurricular activities--party, dinner, athletics, etc; could be associated with Alphi Psi or Omega Tau Sigma Fraternity, Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Men in suits at banquet; flowered wallpaper on back wall and windows with heavy draperies, Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Two men sitting next to a desk covered with paper; sign on the wall "This Herd is Certified Brucellosis Free", Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Two men in white lab coats dissecting a mouse; note on back indicates "Animal Care Panel, Sloan Kettering", Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Three meat inspectors in white lab coats, one on right with white safety helmet, examining meat samples on metal platform, Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Man in white lab coat making notes next to a large bi-focal microscope; labeled "NYSVMS" on back, Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Proof contact sheet with images of surgery on a tiger, Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
    Item number: 33756
  - Meat inspectors with Carmen Scherzo (left), Undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
    Item number: Neg 0020
  - Families with childen walking along trail in summer, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Man holding a pipe at eye level looking down to right, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Man wearing Fedora hat in window facing forward, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Two men in casual clothes standing outside at corner of a white building, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Photo on front of postcard showing Cornell stands of Schoellkopf field?, about 1910-1912; inscription on back to "Miss Anna Roberts", Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Man in mask carrying plaid blankets, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Two men talking at table; one on right has white blazer with Cornell logo, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Two men holding petri dish outside in a field; one with glasses on right in dressed in a business suit, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Three photos taken in a tropical country: water buffalo plowing in a field; horse team pulling a heavy wagon; two people standing next to a horse with rider, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Three men in suits drinking Cornell milk from a vending machine with signs "Cornell Milk" and "Chocolate Milk", Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Man with crew cut in suit standing in front of a projection screen, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Group of students gathered around memorial to Franklin L Sheldon on south side of Goldwin Smith Hall, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Student on bridge over creek, about 1900-1910, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Scientist smoking a pipe in a white jersey adjusting a large instrument, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Muscular mail Cornell athlete standing in shorts and jersey with "c", Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Older man in stripped suit with glasses facing left, Undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Man with brimmed hat holding a handful of 4 light lab-type puppied, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Beagle dog having its bladder tapped for obtaining urine for leptospirosis identification, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
    Item number: E23549
  - Woodchuck used by Dr. Bud C. Tennant for virus research, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Color illustration of two white tailed deer in meadow, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
    Item number: CN-9-95-75
  - White polar bear in zoo enclosure, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Veterinarian standing next to mare and foal with hoof removed in barnyard sh; gift of J.L Wilder, 1901 (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Owl, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Double-headed horse skull, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
    Item number: 5-85-83
  - Horses on racetrack, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Plaque labeled "Kriemhild Herd Holstein-Friesian cattle", New York Holstein Friesian Association 1928, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Man on manure wagon pulled by three horses (2 white) in winter, Undated (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Andre Moul Collection
    - Andre Moul Ross's photograph collection: faculty and staff, Undated (Box 48, Folder 45)
    - Andre Moul Ross's photograph collection: classes, activities, clinics, etc., Undated (Box 48, Folder 46)
    - Andre Moul Ross's photograph collection: contact sheets, Undated (Box 48, Folder 47)
    - Enrollment form, possibly for Andre Moul Ross, Undated (Box 48, Folder 47)